今天幹得不錯 Brenda
Good job today,brenda.
謝謝 Keith 今天收穫不錯
Thanks,keith. This was a great haul.
是啊 今天魚可真願意咬鉤 很久沒這樣了
Yeah. They were really biting today. It's been a while.
不如你先回去吧 我想把剩下的做成熏魚
Why don't you head back to town. I want to put the rest in the smoker.
我載你一程吧
I'll drop you off.
不用 我自己步行回去
No. I could do with the walk.
快回家抱老婆吧
Get home to your wife.
確定嗎? 我等你Lisa也不會介意的
You sure? Lisa wouldn't mind if I waited for you.
我沒事的 回家吧
I'll be fine. Go home.
好吧 別太晚了 好嗎?
All right,well,don't stay too late,all right?
- 好的 明天見 - 好的 再見
- Ok. I'll see you tomorrow. - All right. See you.
誰在那兒?
Is anyone there?
"誰在那兒" Brenda?
"is anyone there," brenda?
搞笑 即使真有殺人狂躲在暗處 他也不會回答
Right. 'cause the homicidal maniac hiding in the shadows is really going to answer you.
Keith?
別惡搞了 這很沒趣
Stop messing around. It's not funny.
哦 是你
Oh,it's you.
我還以為是別人...
I thought someone was...
JJ 問題重點不在這
Jj,that's not the point.
你會給他打電話?
Well,are you gonna call him?
也許吧
Maybe.
Emily
Emily.
Mick Rawson是個傲慢 自負 性慾旺盛的...
Mick rawson is an arrogant,oversexed,egotistical...
而且聲音性感的火辣英國佬 有警徽 有佩槍
Hot british dude with a sexy accent,badge,and gun.
不正是你的菜嗎?
Just your type.
你知道嗎? 有時我真的不瞭解你
You know what? I don't even get you sometimes.
不會有結果的
It wouldn't go anywhere.
不試怎麼知道
You don't know that.
我瞭解我們的工作
I know our work schedules.
知道嗎? Will和我不就協調得挺好
Ok,you know what? Will and I make it work.
不是吧
Oh,no.
我知道 明白 瞭解 別指責我
I know. I know. I know. Don't say it.
看看媕Y的東西再說... 這不是我的錯
But when you see what's in here... And it's not my fault.
我發誓是他們熱情招呼我 而且都是特價
They were calling to me,I swear. And they were all on sale.
我想這樣有助於經濟恢復
And when you think about it,that means that I am helping the economy,
所以我做得比你們好 因為你們啥也沒買
which is more than I can say for you guys,'cause no one else has bags.
別說這些都是給我兒子買的
Yeah. Please tell me all of those aren't for my son.
- 不是 - 很好
- They're not. - Good.
只有這個是給Kevin的
This one is for kevin.
怎麼? 作為教母我理應寵愛我的教子
What? It is my duty as a fairy godmother to spoil the child.
Henry終有一天會長大 他打開禮物的時候會非常開心
And henry is finally old enough to be fun when opening presents.
我可不想去退啊
I'm not taking them back.
把我的咖啡給我 沒人會受傷
Give me my coffee and no one's gonna get hurt.
半咖啡因 加2份脫脂奶精攪勻的 特大杯焦糖瑪奇朵
Oh,uh,half-caf extra shot venti,2- pump nonfat,hold the whip caramel macchiato.
下一站 "世外桃源"
Next stop,xanadu.
等等 "世外桃源"泡湯
Oh,wait. Xana-don't.
得回去開會了 女士們
Time to go to the bau,ladies.
也許我該養隻貓
Maybe I should get a cat.
- 很抱歉毀了你的浪漫之夜 - 怎麼 要努力迎娶第四任妻子嗎?
- Sorry to ruin your night. - What,are you working on wife number 4?
總是躲不開你們啊
I see you people way too much.
我們開始吧
Let's get started.
好的 安克雷奇分局請我們 協助調查阿拉斯加州富蘭克林的連環謀殺案
All right. Anchorage field office is asking us to investigate a series of murders in franklin,alaska.
過去不到一周內有三人遇害
There's 3 people dead in less than a week.
這對一個只有1476人的城市而言太顯著了
For a town with a population of 1,476,that's fairly significant.
這是他們第一次立案調查謀殺案
It's their first murder investigation on record.
誰是受害者?
Who are the victims?
Jon Baker 獵人
Uh,jon baker,a hunter.
Dedaimia Swanson 教師
Dedaimia swanson,a schoolteacher.
Brenda Bright 漁船大副
Brenda bright,the first mate on a fishing boat.
- 平均每2天有1個新的受害者 - 有關聯嗎?
- There's a new victim every 2 days. - Any connections?
顯然這種小城鎮大家都有關聯
Unfortunately,in a town this small,everyone's connected.
謀殺方式不同
Different kill methods.
報告稱前2個受害者都被步槍射殺
It says the first two victims were both shot with a rifle,
但Brenda Bright卻被箭刺兩次?
but brenda bright was stabbed twice with an arrow?
大家確信這是同一個人所為嗎?
Are we sure it's the same guy?
3名受害者均在交通繁忙區被發現
All 3 victims were found in heavily trafficked areas.
這表明不明嫌犯想讓他們終被發現
The unsub wants them found sooner than later.
Jon Baker的屍體暴露在外任由風吹雨打
Jon baker's body was left exposed to the elements,
但兩名女人卻被埋在垃圾堆下 為什麼?
but the two women were buried under mounds of trash. Why?
這可能是懊悔的表現
It could be a sign of remorse.
他掩蓋起屍體 就不用面對殺人的事實
Cover their bodies so he doesn't have to face the reality of what he's done.
或他認為這些女人都是垃圾 他按自己的想法處置他們
Or he thinks that the women are trash and he's just placed them where he thinks they belong.
還沒有任何定論
Well,we can't be sure of anything yet.
富蘭克林是一個獨立的漁業區 受經濟衰退影響很大
Franklin is an isolated fishing community that's been hit really hard by the current economy.
加上這些未破解的連環兇殺案 居民都瀕臨絕境
Add to that a series of unsolved murders and everyone's on edge.
當地的警長深覺力所不逮
The local sheriff's out of his depth.
阿拉斯加州上一次調查連環兇殺 還要追溯到80年代的Robert Hansen案
And alaska hasn't handled a serial investigation since robert hansen in the eighties.
今晚我們乘飛機前往 大家可以在飛機上休息
We'll fly out tonight. Everybody can sleep on the plane.
- Garcia 我需要你同行 - 長官?
- Garcia,I need you with us. - sir?
我已經申請了一條衛星線路 你的工作是確保我們的聯繫
I've tasked a satellite uplink and it's your job to keep us connected.
明白 長官
Yes,sir.
小鎮已經頻臨絕境 如殺手按此模式繼續
This town's already on the brink,and if this pattern continues,
我們僅有一天去阻止下次謀殺 趕緊動身
we've only got another day until the next murder. Let's finish this fast.
犯罪心理 第五季 第21集 絕命出路
Criminal Minds Season05 Episode21 Exit Wounds
"自然 她最叫人目眩神迷的地方在於"
"nature in her most dazzling aspects "or stupendous parts,"
"她是人類悲劇孕育的溫床 上演的舞台" 約翰·莫利(19世紀法國啟蒙主義思想家)
is but the background and theater of the tragedy of man." John morley.
這傢伙展開了他的殺戮 沒有任何性別和種族界限
This guy's all over the map. Crosses sex and race boundaries.
他改變了殺人模式 這表明他很混亂
He changed his kill method. It says to me he's disorganized.
但所有的罪案現場都沒留下指紋 他還孤立了受害者
Yet there weren't prints at any of the crime scenes,and he isolated his victims.
戴手套 確保不被任何人看見 這點傻瓜都知道
Wearing gloves and making sure there aren't any witnesses... That's a no-brainer.
但讓我關注的是謀殺的"進化"
But what concerns me is the evolution of the kills.
"進化"?
Evolution?
開始時他選擇容易的獵物
Well,he started with easy prey.
Jon Baker 60多歲
Jon baker was in his mid sixties.
對於第一次下手而言風險較低
It's relatively low-risk for a first-timer.
Dedaimia Swanson 50歲出頭
Dedaimia swanson was in her early fifties.
她也不難被制服
She wouldn't be that difficult to overpower.
他無需制服他們 前兩個受害者都是被射殺的
But he didn't have to overpower either one of them. Both victims were shot.
這正是我要說的
Which is my point exactly.
他從遠處射殺了他們
He killed them both from a safe distance.
但Brenda Bright年輕 更健壯
But brenda bright was younger,more athletic.
她有能力跟殺手抵抗 所以為什麼不把她也射殺呢?
She would have been able to put up much more of a fight,so why not shoot her,too?
這表明他的行為模式紊亂
That supports the disorganized theory.
也許在前兩名受害者身上 他沒有獲得想要的東西
Maybe he didn't get what he wanted from his first two victims.
Brenda Bright是個吸引人的女人
Brenda bright was an attractive woman.
他用了箭 但並非用箭射殺 而是刺殺
He used an arrow,but he didn't shoot her with it. He stabbed her.
我想大家都明白刺殺的意味
I think we all know what that means.
我們在安克雷奇著陸後 轉乘一架水上飛機去富蘭克林
When we land in anchorage,there'll be a float plane to take us to franklin.
抵達後 Morgan和Prentiss負責現場
When we get there,morgan and prentiss work the crime scene.
我們要搞清殺手是怎麼伏擊受害者的
We need to know exactly how he ambushed his victims.
Reid和Rossi負責屍體 看能有什麼發現
Reid and rossi,the bodies. Find out what you can there.
JJ和我負責被害者研究 Garcia負責鎮上的記錄調查
Jj and I will work victimology. And,garcia,town records.
- 找出一切我們可用的資料 - 當然 長官
- Find us something we can use. - Of course,sir.
我想告知大家當地的信號非常不穩定
I should let everybody know that reception in the area is unreliable at best.
我會發給大家衛星電話用以通訊
I'm giving everybody satellite phones for communication,
我已在所有電話預設了快捷鍵
and I've already preprogrammed all your digits into speed dial.
猜猜誰是幸運的7號
Guess who's lucky number 7.
歡迎來富蘭克林 我是Flack警官
Welcome to franklin. I'm deputy flack.
這是Brenda Bright 被殺那晚工作的碼頭嗎?
Are these the docks that brenda bright was working the night she was killed?
- 是的 - 很好 我們從這媔}始調查
- yes. - All right,we'll get started here.
- Hotchner探員? - 是的
- Agent hotchner? - Yes,sir.
- Rhodes警長 - 很高興見到你
- Sheriff rhodes. - Very nice to meet you.
很高興見到你們
Good to meet you,sir,ma'am.
你們能來我真是太感激了
So I cannot tell you how grateful I am that you all could come.
居民們開始恐慌了
The people here are really starting to act up.
這個小鎮的氣氛一觸即發
I'm afraid our little town's a bit of a powder keg.
我們要安頓在哪
Where would you like us to set up,sir?
是這樣 警局堥S有足夠的地方 因為警局還兼做郵局
You see,there's not much room at the station because that's also the post office.
不過我跟Carol說好了 你們可以在她的旅館堣u作 就在這
But I have made arrangements for you to work out of carol's tavern,which is right over there.
- 謝謝 - 謝謝你們能來
- thank you. - Well,thank you. Appreciate it.
這奡X乎與世隔絕 你們的生活物資從哪來
It's pretty isolated out here. How do you get basic supplies?
水上飛機每周送一次食品和五金用品
Float planes bring grocery and hardware deliveries on a weekly basis,
漁夫和獵人為鎮上居民提供肉類
and fishermen and hunters provide the town's meat supply.
我是Craig Ramey 你們是FBI?
I'm craig ramey. You all the fbi?
你怎麼知道的?
What gave us away?
你要出海捕魚嗎? 帶了不少東西啊
You're sure packing an awful lot of stuff for a fishing trip.
我不是去捕魚的
I'm not going fishing.
在我和我妻子被殺之前 我們要趕快離開
Getting the hell out of dodge before it's me or my wife put in the ground.
你認識Brenda嗎?
Did you know brenda well?
大家都認識她 她很可愛
Everyone did. She was sweet.
她幹起活來 不比碼頭上任何一個男人差
She's pull a haul just as good as any guy on these docks.
等我把房子封起來 我就馬上離開
As soon as I get my house boarded up,I'm heading out.
你最好也別待在這了 Susan 借過
Suggest you do the same,susan.
我也不能怪他
I can't say that I blame him.
出了這種事情 只走了這麼些人 已經不容易了
With what's been going on,i'm surprised more people aren't trying to leave.
這是Keith Graves Brenda遇害的晚上他們在一起
This is keith graves. He was with brenda the night she died.
Graves先生 兇案發生當晚有什麼異常嗎?
Mr. Graves,did you notice anything out of the ordinary the night of the murder?
沒有 我想要等她一起走的 可是她堅持要我先回鎮上
No. I offered to wait for her,but she insisted I head up to town without her.
那天晚上你們做了什麼
What were you two doing that night?
那天的工作結束我就走了
We finished for the day. I left.
她在那處理要帶回家的魚
She stuck around to clean the fish that she wanted to take home.
- 她一直都一個人回家嗎? - 是的
- She usually walk home alone? - Yeah.
Brenda說走路可以昇華靈魂
Brenda said that walking was good for the soul.
這兒離鎮上有多遠
How far is it into town?
大約半英里
About a half a mile.
不明嫌犯可以在任何地方伏擊她
The unsub could have waited for her anywhere.
謝謝你的配合
Appreciate your time.
警長要我在你們來之前 把屍體放在冰上保存
Sheriff asked me to keep everyone on ice till you got here.
我還是很難相信 鎮上有人會做出這種事
Still,I can't believe someone from franklin would be capable of this.
你根據什麼判斷 她是被箭刺死的而不是被槍擊的?
What convinced you she was stabbed with the arrow instead of shot?
刺入點呈向上的角度
Upward angle at the point of entry.
若是射殺 他得在她下方
He would have had to been shooting from beneath her.
屍體已經被野獸吃的殘缺不全了
There wasn't much left. Forest got to him first.
- 我在屍體上發現了尿液 - 尿液?
- I found urine on the remains. - Urine?
我覺得可能是 啃食屍體的動物留下的
I thought it was from the animals who scavenged his body,
但是化驗結果今天早上出來了
but I got the lab results back this morning.
那是人類的尿液 他這是在給受害人做標記嗎
the urine was human. Is he marking his victims?
我只在Jon身上發現了尿液 兩具女性的屍體上都沒有
Only found it on jon. Both the women were clean.
Jon被射了三槍 前兩槍是擦傷 最後一槍正中頭部
Jon was shot 3 times. The unsub grazed him twice and then hit him in the head.
Dedaimia Swanson只被射了一槍
Dedaimia swanson was only shot once.
第一次殺人的時候 嫌犯還很猶豫 不確定
The first kill shows hesitation,uncertainty.
他沒有射出致命一槍的信心
He wasn't confident taking the terminal shot.
他最後開那一槍可能是偶然 或者是被那場景刺激到了
It was either accidental or spur of the moment,
但第二次殺人 他只用了一槍 他進步的很快
but the second kill,he only needed one shot. He's progressing quickly.
你和受害人熟悉嗎
Were you close with the victims?
我是鎮上唯一的醫生 他們都來我這就診
An occupational hazard when you're the only doctor in town.
Brenda還是我接生的 白髮人送黑髮人實在讓人難以接受
I delivered brenda. Never thought I'd outlive her.
看她軀幹上的傷口
Look at the cuts on her torso.
都很淺 而且沒有刺透
They're shallow and non-penetrating.
- 這些傷口不是為了殺她 - 這是死後才刺的
- Not necessary for the murder. - You know what? These were made postmortem.
他在用這些屍體實驗殺人方法
He's playing with the bodies,experimenting with his methodology.
這是個沒有憐憫之心的人
Someone incapable of remorse.
我們遇到是一個變態人格的殺人犯
We're dealing with a psychopath.
你檢查過她是否遭受過性侵犯嗎?
Have you determined whether or not she was raped?
我完全沒想過做這個檢查
I didn't even think to look.
你的報告中說 襲擊是在這發生的
Your report says the assault occurred here.
沒錯 從那個方向有一道血跡延伸過來
That's right. There was a trail of blood coming from that direction.
這堥S有血跡
I don't see any blood.
- 我們把它埋起來了 - 你們破壞了犯罪現場?
- We covered it up. - You contaminated the scene?
我們必須這麼做 樹林埵酗@隻狂暴的熊
We had to. We've got a rabid bear in the woods.
它會把小獵物撕成碎片
It's been ripping smaller game to shreds.
那種動物聞到血腥味 就會毫不猶豫地衝進鎮子
A creature like that smells blood,he'll come into town,no hesitation.
好吧 你說另兩名受害者 被發現的情形和這差不多?
Ok,you said the other two victims were found similar to this?
Jon是在森林邊上被發現的
Jon was found on the edge of the woods.
Dedaimia在上面的瀑布邊被發現
Dedaimia was up by crest falls.
那是很受歡迎的遠足路線
It's a popular hiking route.
- 都有誰知道他們的作息規律? - 大家都知道
- Who would know their routines? - Everyone.
Jace 要喝咖啡嗎?
Cup of coffee,jace?
你在幹什麼?
What are you doing?
讓這地方變得不那麼模擬化
Trying to make this place a little less analog.
抱歉 我知道我的黑客笑話很冷
Sorry. I forget my hacker jokes aren't funny.
我叫Penelope
My name is penelope.
我不帶槍 我的武器就是我的聰明才智
I'm the one who doesn't carry a weapon,aside from my biting wit.
我的工作就是 把我強大的系統 和你們警署的數據結合起來
And my job includes combining my kick-ass systems with your sheriff's department database
然後來調查你們的秘密
to get the skinny on your neighbors and you.
你想知道什麼 可以直接問我們啊
Or you could just ask us what you want to know.
我是說 直截了當的對話 不比窺探隱私要好嗎
I mean,isn't it better to just talk to us directly than look up our dirt secretly?
我不覺得 因為根據我的經驗 網絡信息是可靠的 而人們總會說謊
No. Because in my experience,the information superhighway never lies and people do.
- 你的名字是什麼 - Josh
- Your name would be? - Josh.
我媽媽Carol是這的老闆
My mom carol,she owns the place.
給你看看 有了
It goes like this. Here we are.
Joshua Beardsley 23歲 出生於阿拉斯加 富蘭克林
Joshua beardsley,age 23,born right here in franklin,ak.
初中和高中搬到安克雷奇
Moved to anchorage for middle and high school.
在西雅圖大學主修酒店管理
Majored in hotel management at seattle u.
你幾周前搬回來
And you moved back home a few weeks ago.
時機絕佳啊 一回來 就有人陸續被殺
Perfect timing,huh? I come home,people start dying.
我來看看你的犯罪記錄
That's when I check your criminal record.
我的朋友 你身家清白
And you,my friend,are clean as a whistle.
- 什麼意思? - 不知道
- What does that even mean? - No idea.
不是開玩笑 所以我現在安全了?
No dirt,anyway,so,I guess I'm safe,then?
目前為止
For now.
這兩個昨晚進來的
Those two got into it last night.
這是Bob 他是新來的
Bob here,he's our newest resident,
所以Tom認為所有謀殺 都是他一人幹的
so,uh,tom figures,well,this is the guy who's doing all the killings.
於是決定用酒瓶砸爛他腦袋
He decides to smash him over the head with a bottle of booze.
聽著 我不知道怎麼辦
Look,I don't know what to do.
你有沒有想過開個大會
Have you thought about having a kind of town hall meeting
把大家聚在一起 討論這個案子?
where you get everybody together and talk about the facts of the case?
這個鎮子太鬆散了
The town's too spread out.
每個人只是得過且過
I mean,everybody's doing what they can just to get by,you know?
警長 我知道 人們搬到這些邊遠地區 就是求清靜
Sheriff,I know people move to these remote locations to be left alone,
但昨晚發生的事 不會就此停止
but what happened last night is gonna keep happening,
慢慢下去 每個人都清靜不了了
and people are going to start taking matters into their own hands.
我可以管好自己這個鎮 但周圍的人 這兒可是阿拉斯加
Well,I can keep order in my own town,but people around here,I mean,this is alaska,man.
他們為所欲為
They do what they want.
他已經在受害者身上進行了實驗
He's already experimenting with his victims.
他用箭對Brenda Bright施暴
He violated brenda bright with an arrow.
不斷激起居民恐慌
And he's inciting panic.
在這埵矰F大半輩子的人 都打包準備離開
People who have lived here most of their lives are packing up to leave.
這能怪他們嗎?
Can you blame them?
這埵陪蚥傴A狂 作案範圍就是這1400人的小鎮
We have a psychopath whose hunting ground is a town of 1,400 people.
大多數居民 從小學習狩獵和生火
Most of them grew up learning to kill animals and start fires.
聽上去像基本生存技能
It sounds like your basic survival skills.
不 是狩獵技能
No. They're hunting skills.
想想看 那種槍法 那些尿液 是有意義的
Think about it. The marksmanship,the urine... It makes sense.
尿液也有意義?
The urine makes sense?
這是獵人的計謀 順風尿尿 以趨散動物
It's a hunter's trick. You urinate downwind to keep the animals away.
他想方設法保存Jon Baker的屍體 好讓它原封不動的被發現
He tried to preserve jon baker's body so it would be discovered intact.
這下好了 變態狂具備狩獵技巧 還瞭解鎮上人們的作息時間
All right,so we've got a psychopath with hunting skills who knows the routines of everyone in town.
我們如何保障大家的安全?
How are we supposed to keep everyone safe?
警長 我建議你制定宵禁 直到我們抓獲不明嫌犯
Sheriff,I suggest you institute a curfew until we have the unsub in custody.
天黑後不得外出
Nobody out after dark.
我會保證有警官日夜巡邏
I'll have one of my deputies patrolling around the clock.
Garcia 鎮上的記錄如何?
Garcia,how's it coming with town records?
我查遍了CODIS系統 沒有發現有價值的信息
I've run everyone who's been printed through codis. Nothing's come up so far.
今晚熬夜核對完所有記錄
I'm gonna pull an all-nighter,finish going through the town records.
- 明早應該能有背景資料了 - 好
- Should have background checks by sunrise. - Good.
剩下的人抓緊睡一會兒 明早有個好精神
The rest of us should get some sleep,start fresh in the morning.
樓上有四個空房間
I've got 4 of the upstairs rooms available.
- 4個? - 別這樣 我們就這個條件
- Uh,4? - come on,that's the best we can do.
你們團隊人數是我部門的兩倍
Your team is double the size of my department.
- 明早見 - 晚安
- I'll see you in the morning. - good night.
- 得兩人一間了 - 我不跟Reid睡
- It looks like we'll have to double up. - I'm not sleeping with reid.
我跟你了
Dibs.
什麼意思 你要跟Morgan一個房間?
What do you mean,you're sharing a room with morgan?
你吃醋了
Oh,you're jealous.
吃醋? 因為什麼? ... 因為跟你共眠的人是...
Jealous? Why? Because you're bedding down with a...
當代肌肉版007?
Muscle-bound,modern-day 007?
他更像伯恩
Mm,he's more like jason bourne.
還問我有什麼好吃醋的?
Oh,what's there to be jealous about?
他睡地板
He took the floor.
確保他把槍裝在皮套 好嗎?
Ok. Just... Just make sure he keeps his weapon holstered,ok?
你怎麼還沒睡? 已經很晚了
Why are you up right now,anyway? It's so late.
還很早 我剛到匡提科
Actually,it's early. I just got to quantico.
可惡的時差
Damn time zones.
喂?
- Hello? - Hello?
Hello?
信號中斷 衛星傳輸受到干擾 超出轄區範圍 無法連接
見鬼了
Frak.
別這樣
Oh,come on,baby.
加油 加油 加油
Come on,come on,come on.
幹得好 Garcie
Nice one,garcie.
看著我 你會沒事的
Look at me. You're gonna be ok.
我叫Penelope 你會沒事的
My name's penelope. You're gonna be ok. You're gonna be ok.
一直看著我
Just keep looking at me.
救命! 救命!
Help! Help! Please!
快來人!
Somebody come help here!
有人受傷了! 救命!
Someone is hurt! Please!
他叫Craig Ramey 是個漁民
His name's craig ramey. Fisherman.
我跟Morgan今早遇見他
Morgan and I met him this morning.
他正收拾準備離開
He was packing up to leave.
他提前了作案時間
He's accelerating his schedule.
我們應該還有一天 為什麼改變?
We should have had another day. Why change that?
對於離開鎮子一事 Ramey頗為高調
Ramey was pretty vocal about wanting to get out of town.
如果不明嫌犯知道了 便會提前下手 阻止目標逃走
If the unsub knew that,he could have struck early to prevent his target from getting away.
應該不僅僅只這樣
There has to be more to it than that.
他把屍體帶到我們所在的酒館
He brought the body to the tavern we're staying at.
他要告訴我們 他不怕我們 他越來越自信了
He's telling us that he's not afraid of us. He's gaining confidence.
他改用獵刀 像是鋸齒刃的
He switched to a hunting knife. Looks like a jagged edge.
還有一些損傷 像是人被割開了
There's more physical damage,too,like he was cut open.
要等Johnson醫生做屍檢之後才知道
I won't know until dr.Johnson does an autopsy,
但我打賭他割走了 受害者的一塊肉
but I'd be willing to bet he took a piece of the victim with him.
哪堛漱@塊?
What kind of piece?
很難說 但從位置上看 我猜是肝臟或者脾臟
It's hard to say,but judging from the location,I would guess liver or spleen.
他當時還活著
He was alive.
什麼?
What?
他當時依然活著
He was still alive.
親愛的 你無能為力
Baby,there's nothing else you could have done.
我感受到他的逝去
I felt him leave.
前一秒他還在的... 後一秒就沒了知覺
He was there one second,and then... Just a body.
我很難過你看到這些
I'm really sorry that you had to see all of that.
Derek 我...我不只是看到 而是參與其中
Derek,I...I didn't see,I was in it.
我習慣了每天安全地在屏幕上 看可怕的事物 但這個是...
I was sort of used to seeing horrible things from the safety of my screens every day,but this was...
親眼所見
Right there.
為什麼不直接跑開去找人幫忙?
Why didn't you go and find someone before you ran out there?
我記得自己中槍時 心媟Q著 這輩子記得的最後一樣東西
Because when I got shot,I remember thinking the last thing I'm ever gonna see in this life
就是兇手的臉 我不希望在他身上重演
is the man who killed me, and I couldn't let that happen to him.
他死之前應該 看到些美好的東西
He had to see something good before he died.
你直接跑向不明嫌犯 你可能被殺
You ran right towards the unsub. You could have been killed.
我知道 別說的好像我是受害者
I know that. Don't treat me like I'm the victim.
好吧 對不起
All right. I'm sorry.
我想問你幾個問題行嗎?
I want to ask you a couple of questions,all right?
不 我... 我所有看見的都說了
No. I... I told you everything I saw.
你是在黑暗中看到那個男人的臉 又有許多血跡
You said the man's face was mostly in shadow,but there was also a lot of blood on it.
你看到的 可能比你意識到的更多
You might have seen more than you actually realize.
不 這些認知談話 用科學和統計來分析人的死...
No. Cognitive interviews,breaking someone's death down to a science and statistic...
- 那是你的工作 Derek 不是我的! - Penelope!
- That is your world,derek,not mine! - Penelope!
- 我會以我的方式提供幫助 - Penelope!
- I will help from mine. - Penelope!
Derek 隨她去吧
Derek,let her go.
你照看好她 行嗎?
Will you look after her,please?
沒問題
Yeah,of course.
Garcia給你新信息了嗎?
Was garcia able to give you any new information?
- 她盡她所能了 - 這個傢伙在戲弄我們 總是比我們早一步
- She's given all she can. - This guy's taunting us. He's one step ahead.
我想你高看他了
I think you're giving him more credit than he deserves.
正如Emily在飛機上說的 他沒有特定目標
It's like emily said on the plane,he's all over the place.
受害者類型前後不一致 方法在不斷"改進"
The victimology's inconsistent,the methodology's evolving,
第一起謀殺是草率的 遲疑的 未經計劃的
the first kill was sloppy,hesitant,and unplanned.
那是個意外 但卻引發了生理反應 他在這事情上得到了釋放
It was an accident,but it triggered a sexual response. He got off on it.
清楚了這一點 殺戮就停不下來了
And he knew then and there he had to kill again.
他學會了如何更有效率
He learned how to get the job done more efficiently.
沒錯 但割下器官是為什麼呢?
Yeah,but why the organs?
取走部分屍體 非常典型地表明 他把被害者留在身邊的渴望
Consumption typically indicates a desire to keep the victim with them.
他無法放手 我們要找的人 很可能有嚴重的被遺棄問題
He's having trouble letting go. We're probably looking for someone with severe abandonment issues.
很快就天亮了 把所有人集中起來 梳理下已知的情況
It'll be light soon. Let's get everybody together and go over what we know.
我們要找的 是一個感情上很不成熟的男性
we're looking for an emotionally immature male,
很可能在25-30歲之間 曾遭受過創傷性的損失
probably in his mid to late twenties,who suffered a traumatic loss.
可能是任何方面的損失
Now,this loss could be anything.
父母亡故 與配偶分居 所愛的人遷居他處
Death of a parent,separation of a spouse,a loved one who moved away.
某種 讓不明疑犯覺得 被拋棄了 覺得孤獨的事
Something that made the unsub feel abandoned and alone.
他有豐富的狩獵經驗
He'll have extensive hunting experience.
埋屍 不是因為後悔
The bodies were buried not because of remorse,
是為防止被野生動物破壞
they were buried to protect them from wild animals.
他對被害人的日程之熟悉 顯示出 不明疑犯這輩子大部分時間都住這
His familiarity with the victims' routines suggests the unsub has lived here for most of his life.
他對環境與地形瞭如指掌
He also has extensive knowledge of the landscape and surroundings.
所以 我們分頭行動覆蓋全鎮
So we should split up and cover the town.
重點查有輕微犯罪以及 襲擊記錄的青年居民
Focus on younger residents with a history of petty crimes and assaults.
你們應該檢查它們的 垃圾 壁爐 甚至是髒衣服
You should look in their trash,fireplaces,even in laundry.
尋找血衣 割傷 以及淤青的跡象
Look for signs of bloody clothes or even cuts and bruises.
可能有被害者在死前 結結實實地給他來了一兩下子
One of the victims may have gotten in a good blow or two before they died.
看起來有事瞞著的人 就帶回來
bring in anyone who seems to have something to hide.
不明疑犯已經打破了作案模式 他隨時都有可能再次作案
The unsub has already broken patterns,so he could strike again at any time.
警長 你和我去學校看看 跟老師聊聊
Sheriff,you and I need to look at the school,talk to the teacher,
看她是否記得有什麼學生 表現出殺人傾向的早期跡象
see if she remembers any students exhibiting early signs of homicidal tendencies.
我們行動吧
Let's move.
Dedaimia還差一個月就退休了
Dedaimia was only one month away from retirement.
我真不敢相信 她去世了
I can't believe she's gone.
我們深感遺憾
We're very sorry for your loss.
我們得問問你以前學生的情況
I need to ask about your former students.
您記得有誰 過分熱衷打獵 過分到讓您擔心的地步嗎?
Do you remember any of them enjoying hunting too much,so much that it worried you?
這堜狾釭漕k孩子都喜歡得不得了
All the boys around here like it too much.
他們還比賽看誰槍法更准呢
They have competitions to see who's the better shot.
這個人應該是到了偏激的程度
This would have been extreme.
有沒有人 在殺死動物之前 會折磨它們或者跟它們玩嗎?
Do you remember anyone who might have tortured animals or played with them before he killed them?
想起什麼人來了嗎?
Does that sound like someone you know?
我從沒見過有人 像Joshua Beardsley那樣熱衷狩獵
I've never seen anyone enjoy hunting as much as joshua beardsley.
- 他是酒館老闆的兒子? - 沒錯
- He's the tavern owner's son? - Yeah.
全鎮最年輕的獵到鹿的男孩子
The youngest boy in town to bag a deer.
他從來就只談這些
That's all he ever talked about.
他幾乎每天都獵點什麼
He hunted something nearly every day.
他土生土長
He was born and raised here.
父親過世後 他回來了 就在幾周前
He returned a couple of weeks ago after his dad died.
他多大了?
How old is he?
- 23? - 沒錯
- 23? - Sure.
- 我們得去跟他談談 - 好吧
- We need to talk to him. - All right.
謝謝你
Thank you.
這是為啥事?
What's this about?
並未傷及內臟
The strike was above the gut.
這會使肉不至於腐壞 對吧?
It keeps the meat from spoiling. Isn't that right?
對鹿來說 也許吧
On a deer,maybe.
對人來說 估計就不一定了
Doubt it'd be the same for a human.
但接著他做了件有意思的事情
But then he did something interesting.
他取走了被害人的脾臟
He took the victim's spleen.
告訴我 他為什麼要這麼做?
Now,tell me,why would he do that?
不知道
No idea.
我們就別耍花樣了Joshua
Let's stop playing games,joshua.
回答我的問題 或許我會相信你的
Answer my questions and maybe I'll believe you.
這是本地的狩獵傳統 不是嗎?
It's a native hunting tradition,isn't it?
吃下殺掉的生靈的一部分
Eat part of the kill.
獲取你的獵物的生命力
Gain the life force of your prey.
知道這個的人可不多
Not many people know that.
可我知道
I'm not many people.
你在哪學會的狩獵?
Where did you learn to hunt?
7歲的時候就獵獲了我的第一隻鹿
Bagged my first deer when I was 7.
那是挺早的
That's pretty young.
我父親教會我如何靠大地為生
My dad taught me how to live off the land.
我吃掉了我第一隻獵物的心臟
I ate the heart of my first kill.
這證明你是個真正的獵人
That proves you're a true hunter.
這麼說 你...折衷狩獵?
So,you,um,enjoy hunting?
這是我最愛做的事情
It's my favorite thing to do.
那 你在殺戮中獲得快樂嗎?
Then would you say you take pleasure in the kill?
大家不都是嗎?
Doesn't everyone?
實際上 不 不是的
Actually,no...They don't.
- 你怎麼看? - 我不確定
- What do you think? - I'm not sure.
他符合側寫 但他表現得十分坦蕩
He fits the profile,but he's acting like a man with nothing to hide.
襲擊週期在縮短 他今晚要作案
The attack cycle's accelerating. He should strike tonight.
要是沒有出手 那我們就已經抓對人了
And if he doesn't,we know we've got our guy in custody.
要是他今晚下手呢?
And what if he does?
看 我不想說這話 但是這鎮上 有一半人都符合你們的側寫
Look,I hate to say it,but half this town matches most of your profile.
大家在忙什麼呢?
What are you guys working on?
Hotch叫我們看Garcia給的背景資料
Hotch asked if we'd go through garcia's background profiles,
試著找出Joshua與4名被害人的聯繫
try to find a link between joshua and the 4 victims.
你發現什麼了嗎?
You find anything?
他們都有狩獵執照
They all had hunting licenses.
大海撈針啊 我們需要大人物出手
Needle,meet haystack. Yeah,we need the big guns.
正摩拳擦掌準備幹架呢
Ripped and ready to rumble.
或許這一次 你就不用參與了
Uh,maybe you should sit this one out.
不 JJ 我沒事
No,jaje,I'm ok.
把這雜種送到他該去的地方
Put this bastard where he belongs.
- Joshua Beardsley? - 是的 我們認為他是不明疑犯
- Joshua beardsley? - Yeah. We think he's our unsub.
不 他不是
No,he's not.
他符合側寫 最近父親過世 引發他被遺棄的情緒
He fits the profile. Abandonment issue triggered by his father's recent death.
- Reid... - 狩獵經驗
- reid... - Hunting experience,
- 用動物做實驗 - Reid
- Experimentation with animals. - Reid.
你們逮捕了我兒子?
You arrested my son?
我們把他帶去 是為了以防萬一
We brought him in as a precaution.
我告訴你 不是他
I'm telling you,it's not him.
- 你為什麼怎麼肯定? - 因為不明疑犯丟下我跑了
- What makes you so sure? - Because the unsub ran away from me.
他當然會跑 他知道你是FBI
Of course he ran. He knew you were fbi.
但Joshua知道我只是技術人員 他知道我沒有配槍
But joshua knows i'm a techie. He knows I don't carry a weapon.
他要是不明疑犯 我早死了
If he was the unsub,i'd be dead right now.
你怎麼能聽信這些呢 Steve?
How can you be listening to any of this,steve?
你知道Joshua絕不會做這種事的
You know joshua would never do this.
看 我從沒想過 我們中有誰能做出這樣的事
Look,I never thought any of us were capable of doing this.
但死了四個人了 Carol
But 4 people are dead,carol.
你不瞭解他 他是個好孩子
You don't know him. He's a good boy.
他是個近期喪父 情緒壓力很大的好孩子
He's a good boy who recently lost his father and it's a lot of emotional stress.
是挺不容易的 但正在面對 他處理得不錯
It's been tough,but we're coping. He's doing fine.
他為什麼搬回鎮上來?
Why did he move back to town?
我需要他在這媕飢琤散z客棧 我自己一個人顧不過來
I needed him here to help with the inn. I can't handle it on my own.
那對此他怎麼想? 不得不放棄一切搬回來
And how did that make him feel,having to drop everything and move back home?
- 這不是他幹的 - 我們得確定
- He didn't do this. - we need to be sure.
我很肯定 我是他母親
I'm sure. I'm his mother.
Carol 就一個晚上
Carol,it's one night.
要是不出事 你明早來接他
If nothing happens,you pick him up in the morning.
等一下 你說不明疑犯有被遺棄問題
Wait a minute. You said the unsub has abandonment issues.
而Craig Ramey打算離開本鎮 對吧?
And craig ramey was leaving town,right?
是啊 他都等不及要從鎮上搬出去了
Yeah,he couldn't wait to get out of town.
好的 我們看一看
ok. Uh... Let's see.
Dedaimia Swanson還有一個月就退休了
Dedaimia swanson was retiring in a month.
- 她正準備搬去佛羅里達 - 另外那倆呢?
- She was moving to florida. - What about the other two?
Jon Baker剛在費爾班克斯買了房子 而且他和他妻子剛分開
Un,jon baker just bought property in fairbanks,and he and his wife just separated.
她剛遞了離婚協議
She just filed the divorce papers.
哇 歡迎回來 紅髮寶貝
Well,welcome back,red delicious.
來看看這個
Take a bite out of this.
到目前為止 3個受害人 都踏上了離開這鎮的快速列車
So far,3 of our victims were on the fast track to getting out of town.
再看一下... 第四個也是
And let's see... Connect 4.
Brenda剛接受了在西雅圖的工作
Brenda just accepted a job in seattle.
還有誰看上去 有可能會離開鎮子的?
Anyone else look like they might be leaving town?
找到一個 Kat Allen
Um... I got one. Kat allen.
她剛被布魯明頓大學的夏季課程錄取了
She was accepted to the summer honors program at the university of bloomington.
她目前在Big John咖啡館當侍應
She currently works as a waitress at big john's coffeehouse.
- Penelope 你真的是... - 準備好要回家了
- Penelope,you are... - So ready to go home.
Prentiss
Prentiss.
我們找Kat Allen
We're looking for kat allen.
我就是Kat
I'm kat.
我們能談一下嗎?
Can we talk?
一切都在意料之外
It was completely unexpected.
沒結過婚 本來已經放棄要生孩子了
Never been married. I'd given up on ever having kids.
我能問一下孩子他爸是誰嗎?
Do you mind my asking who the father is?
在遊艇上認識的
A guy I met on a cruise.
他不想認她 但我決定把她生下來
He doesn't want anything to do with her. But I do.
我想給她一個好的生活壞境 所以我要重返學校了
I want to be able to give her a good life,so I'm going back to school.
你跟別人提起過你要離開這嗎?
Did you tell anyone that you were leaving?
是的 幾個人吧
Yeah. A couple of people.
我記不清了...我媽媽 我老闆
Uh,I don't know... My mom. My boss.
我們需要你跟我們走一趟
We're going to need you to come with us.
為什麼? 這是怎麼回事?
Why? What's this about?
就今晚一晚 為了保護你的安全
It's just for tonight. It's for your protection.
該死的
Damn it.
鄰居看見門開著 就報了警
The neighbors saw the door open,called it in.
他從在公開場合埋伏殺人到闖入民宅
He went from ambushing people in public to home invasion.
這作案手法的變化也忒大了
That's a pretty big change in m.o.
這次是私仇 很憤怒
This one's personal. It's angry.
她的腸被割的到處都是
Her intestines are splayed out everywhere.
是的 而且她臉上的血跡被塗抹過 不是剛被濺上時的狀態
Yeah. And the blood on her face is smeared,not splattered.
他虐待過屍體 侵害她的遺體
He played with the body. He mutilated her.
如果他的目標是打算離開鎮子的人 為什麼殺的不是Kat Allen?
if this guy's killing people leaving town,why didn't he attack kat allen?
因為她在我們的保護監禁下
Because we had her in protective custody.
他動不了她 就轉移了目標
He couldn't get to her,so he moved on to another target.
目標打破了自己原本的行程
A target who broke her routine.
Carol今晚本來應該留在酒館的
Carol was scheduled to be at the tavern tonight.
不明嫌犯怎麼知道她回家了?
How did the unsub know she was here?
他跟蹤她
He was stalking her.
他殺Carol的原因和之前的不一樣
He chose carol for a different reason.
為什麼? 什麼變了?
Why? What's changed?
你們終於知道我是無辜的啦?
You guys finally realize i'm innocent?
Joshua 請坐下吧
Joshua,please have a seat.
還有問題要問? 你不是吧?
More questions? You serious?
我告訴你 我沒做過
I'm telling you,I didn't do this.
我們知道 請坐下
We know that,son. Please,sit down.
怎麼回事?
What's going on?
Josh 兇手昨晚又殺人了
Josh,the...The killer struck again last night.
天啊 他這次殺誰了?
Ohh,god. Who did he get?
為什麼你們就告訴我這一件事?
Why are you guys only telliling me this?
我媽在哪?
Where's my mom?
不 不 不 不不不不
no. no. No. No,no,no,no.
不不不 不可能
No,no,no,that's impossible.
她剛剛還在這的 我剛剛還跟她說話來著!
She... She was just here. I... I just talked to her!
我很遺憾 Joshua 她走了
I'm sorry,joshua. She's gone.
不 不不 你們在騙我
Oh,no. No,no,no,no. No,no. You... You're lying.
我也希望我們是
I wish we were.
- 我要見她 - 現在還不行
- I need to see her. - not right now.
你不想見她現在的樣子
You don't want to think of her that way.
Joshua 我們知道你需要時間平復 但事實是
Joshua,we know you need time to mourn,but the fact of the matter is,
兇手還沒抓到 而你能幫我們找到他
the man who did this is still out there,and we think that you can help us find him.
她被殺的時候...我卻被你們鎖在這
You had me locked up while she was...
我本來可以幫她的
I could have helped her.
如果當時你和她在一起 你很有可能也被殺了
If you had gone to her,there's a good chance you'd both be dead.
- 我們需要你的幫助 - 為什麼是我?
- Now we need your help. - Why me?
這些兇殺發生在你回來之後
The murders began when you returned to town.
直到現在 他的目標都是打算離開這鎮上的人
Now,up until now,he's only targeted people who were trying to leave,
但因為某些原因 他和你媽媽卻是有私仇
but for some reason,with your mother,it was personal.
FBI來這媯馴L增加了壓力
the pressure's on. The fbi is here.
在這種情況下 連環殺手通常就想去完成他的最終目的
In that situation,a serial killer wants to finish what he started,
- 去攻擊他真正的目標 - 私人仇恨?
- he goes after the true target of his cause. - Personal?
你能想到有什麼人很怨恨她? 任何人?
Can you think of anyone who had a grudge against her? Anyone at all?
或者有什麼人怨恨你?
How about anyone with a grudge against you?
沒有 沒有 所有人都很喜歡她
No. No. Everybody loved her.
這人有很嚴重的被遺棄問題
The man that we're looking for has severe abandonment issues.
你能想起 你和你媽媽 什麼時候離開過什麼人嗎?
Now,can you think of a time when you or your mother left somebody,
或許一次可怕的分手 或者因為爭吵破壞了友誼?
maybe like a bad break-up or a fight that ended a friendship?
你媽媽曾經在酒館收留過 有家庭問題的人嗎?
Did your mother ever take anyone in at the inn who had family problems,
或者某個被趕出家門的人? 或者突然失去了親人的人?
maybe someone who had been kicked out or lost someone unexpectedly?
不 沒有 沒有這樣的事
No. No,no,no,no,there was nothing like that.
我想在能去看我媽媽了嗎?
Uh,listen,can I go see my mom now?
Josh Josh 你需要讓他們幫忙
Josh. Josh,you need to let these people help.
不 我需要的是...去見我媽媽
No,I need...I need to see my mom.
- 找個人帶你去吧 - 沒事 我認識路
- Well,let's have someone take you. - It's ok. I know the way.
你注意到他的變化嗎? 從想幫助我們 到要急著離開 他在說謊
Did you see his behavior shift from wanting to help us to wanting to leave? He's lying.
因為他知道不明嫌犯是誰
Because he knows who the unsub is.
我叫了一個警官跟著Joshua了
I got one of my deputies tailing joshua.
如果他想幹什麼蠢事 我們會知道的
If he does something stupid,we're gonna know.
我們一定忽略了些當中的聯繫 Garcia 有什麼發現嗎?
There's got to be a connection we're missing. Garcia,anything?
他們的生活真是一團糟 我什麼都沒找到
Their lives have been torn apart,figuratively and literally,and I can't find anything.
重新試一次
Try again.
我正在黑入他大學的資料庫
I'm hacking into his college database as we speak.
或許對於他西雅圖的生活 我之前落了些什麼吧
Maybe there's something about his life in seattle I may have missed.
好 為什麼是Carol? 為什麼要侵害屍體? 為什麼要過度殺害?
Good. All right,why carol? Why the mutilation? Why the overkill?
侵害屍體?
Mutilation?
你說過 你在樹林媯o現了一些 被熊侵害過的動物遺體?
You said you found the remains of mutilated animals in the woods from a rabid bear?
- 沒錯 - 照下來了嗎?
- That's right. - Did you take pictures of them?
當然有
Of course we did.
我們記錄了所有能鑒定身份的東西
We documented everything for identification.
我們現在就要看看那些照片
We'll need to see those pictures right away.
- 警長 我們需要調整之前的側寫 - 什麼意思?
- Sheriff,we need to adjust the profile. - What do you mean?
這些動物屍體不是被熊糟蹋的
These animals weren't mutilated by a rabid bear.
是人為的
Someone did this.
- 你的意思是 一個人 - 如果是動物 不會留下那麼多遺體的
- You mean a person. - An animal wouldn't have left so much.
我們之前就應該想到 這是典型的行兇前兆
We should have seen it before. It's homicidal triad 101.
我們之前說過 兇手沒有特定目標 特定模式
We said the kills were all over the map.
不明嫌疑人沒有經驗 行兇時不成熟 因為他本身就不夠成熟
The unsub lacks sophistication and shows immaturity in his kills because he is immature.
他拿動物做試手 是因為他從小就被教成這樣
He started with animals because that's what he was taught ever since he was a child.
當他試煩了動物 他就向更有難度的目標挑戰
and when he got bored with animals,he moved on to more challenging prey.
- 人類 - 不明嫌犯是一個青少年
- People. - Your unsub's a teenage boy.
我們之前說過的男孩 他不是曾經就讀於此
The boy we were talking about before,he wouldn't be a former student,
而是在校生 一個非常迷戀打獵的青少年
he'd be a current student,a teenager who loves to hunt.
我這堬{在只有兩個青少年 而且都是女的
I only have two teenagers right now. Both of them are girls.
說吧 Garcia
Go ahead,garcia.
我發現一件超詭異的事
I found something uber weird.
Joshua在申請大學的文章
In joshua's college application essay,
寫到了為人兄長對他生活的影響
he talks about the impact that being an older brother had on his life.
我記得他沒有兄弟姐妹
I thought he didn't have any siblings.
他沒有 但他還是提到 棄兄弟於不顧有多艱難
He doesn't,and yet he's talking about how hard it was to leave him behind
在他搬去安克雷奇之後 讓他缺乏保護
when he moved to anchorage,to leave him unprotected.
謝謝
Thanks.
Joshua搬家前 有沒有罩著什麼學生?
Was there a student that joshua may have taken under his wing before he moved away?
你覺得可能遭受虐待的人?
Someone you may have suspected was being abused?
- 我的天啊 - 怎麼了?
- Oh,my god. - What?
Owen Porter 他輟學在家了
Owen porter. He's not a student anymore. He's home-schooled.
他倆穿一條開襠褲長大的
Joshua and he were attached at the hip when they were younger.
我被叫去Porter家幾次
I've been called out to the porter house several times.
家庭暴力
Domestic disturbance.
Owen和他媽媽一直護著爸爸
Owen and his mom always covering for the dad.
- 咱們走 - 謝了
- Let's go. - Thanks.
說說遺棄問題
Talk about abandonment issues.
Owen落入父親手中任其宰割
Owen was left victim to the abusive hand of his father.
Joshua回來 擾亂了Owen的精神狀態
Joshua's return probably derailed owen's mental stability.
加上意外擊中Jon Baker 他崩潰了
Add to that the accidental shooting of jon baker and he snapped.
- 他享受初次殺戮的快感 - 他一定要再來一次
- He got off on that first killing. - He had to do it again.
所以他瞄準要離開小鎮的人
So he targeted people trying to leave town.
在他看來 有人離開 他就會受到傷害
In his mind,when people leave,he gets hurt.
Carol奪走Joshua 他記恨在心 所以殺了她 他就再也不會走了
And he resented carol for taking joshua away,so he killed her to make sure he never left again.
他現在會去哪兒?
Where would he go now?
我們依山傍水 他隨處可去
We're surrounded by waterways and mountains. He could be anywhere.
- Porter先生 你兒子在家嗎? - 關你鳥事?
- Mr. Porter,is your son at home? - What's it to you?
關了電視
Turn that off.
- 你知道了嗎? - 不知道你在說啥!
- Did you know? - Don't know what you're talking about!
不確定 直到昨天晚上
Not for sure. Not until last night.
- 他渾身是血地回來 - 他不在這兒 窗戶開著
- He came home covered in blood. - He's not here. But the window's open.
這不是你第一次 幫他洗掉身上的血跡了吧?
It's not the first time you've washed blood out of his clothes,is it?
- 別理他們 Martha! - 坐下 別插嘴
- Don't answer them,martha! - Sit down and shut up.
我保證他不會再傷害你了
I promise he will not lay a hand on you again.
不 不是第一次了
no. It wasn't the first time.
Porter太太 我知道你只是 想保護Owen 但是你不能這樣了
Mrs. Porter,I understand you're only trying to protect owen,but you can't anymore.
他一直都與眾不同 他不像我們
He's always been different. He's not like us.
他小的時候就經常到森林堨h 帶著一身血回來
When he was a little boy,he used to go out into the woods and come home covered in blood.
你為什麼不告訴別人 Martha?
Why didn't you tell anyone,martha?
你眼睜睜看著別人死掉 怎麼還能還坐得住?
How could you just sit there and do nothing while people died?
Joshua被送走時Owen什麼反應?
How did owen react when joshua was sent away?
他也想走
He wanted to leave,too.
但是我不許
But I couldn't let him.
Porter太太 你知道社交隔離 會對小孩造成什麼影響嗎?
Mrs. Porter,do you have any idea what social isolation does to a child?
我擔心他離開這媟|出亂子
I was afraid of what he might do if he ever left here.
我們知道 我們早知道他是什麼樣的
We knew. We knew what he was.
- 大事不妙 - 怎麼回事?
- We've got a problem. - What is it?
Joshua甩掉了Stiller警官
Joshua managed to shake deputy stiller.
有人舉報說森林埵閉撢y活動
And someone reported a hunting party going into the woods.
天吶
Oh,god.
他們在追捕Owen
They're hunting owen.
聽 在那邊 走
Listen. That way. Go.
- 能打著嗎? - 不行 他跑得太快了
- You have him? - No. He's moving too fast.
他好像是要兜回鎮上
Looks like he's circling back towards town.
開一槍試試
Maybe we'll get lucky.
- 他們剛才開槍了? - 不能接近就會開槍
- Did they just shoot him? - They would be shooting if they weren't close.
快走
Let's go.
你知道他會去哪兒嗎?
Do you know where he's headed?
有他能獨處的地方嗎?
Was there a place he went to be alone?
你們生他氣的時候的藏身之處?
A hiding spot when you were mad at him?
藏身之處 我們怎麼知道?
Hiding spot. How the hell are we supposed to know?
知道的話一定要告訴我
If you know,you need to tell me.
我這是在幫他 有一夥暴徒在找他
I'm trying to help him.There's a mob out there,
他們抓到他 不會把他緝拿歸案
and if they find him,they're not gonna turn him over.
而是就地正法
They're gonna take justice into their own hands.
要是重視你兒子的性命 就幫我
If you value your son's life,you need to help me.
Martha 不要!
Martha,don't!
Lafayette湖
Lake lafayette.
他和Joshua小時候在那兒蓋了城堡
He and joshua built a fort there when they were younger.
得划船逆流而上
You'll need a boat upriver to get there.
同志們等一下
Hold on,guys.
Hotch 什麼事?
Yeah,hotch,what's up?
好 知道了 計劃有變
Ok. I got it. There's a new plan.
他要去碼頭
He's heading for the harbor.
- Owen 把槍放下 - 放下槍 孩子
- Owen,put the gun down. - Drop it,son.
信我們還是信他們?
Who do you want to take your chances with,us or them?
放下武器 退後!
Drop the weapons and back away!
恕難從命 這孩子歸我們了
Can't do that,agents. The boy's coming with us.
- 沒門! - 退後 Keith 這兒歸我們管了
- It's not happening! - Back down,keith. We're in control now.
你想幹什麼 Steve? 他才16歲
What are you gonna do,steve? He's 16.
送他到少管所 關兩年就出來?
Send him back to juvey so he's out in 2 years?
- 他殺了Brenda - 他殺了我媽媽
- He killed my mom. - He killed brenda.
他需要幫助 他會對所犯罪行負責的
He needs help and he will be held accountable for his crimes.
負責? 死了5個人吶
Accountable? 5 people are dead.
你為什麼要那麼做 Owen? 為什麼要殺了她?
Why'd you do it,owen? Why'd you kill her?
- 你拋下我走了 - 你殺了我媽媽!
- You left me behind. - You killed my mom!
是她把你送走的!
She sent you away!
你一去不回
You left and you didn't come back.
8年了 音信全無
8 years and I never heard from you again.
拜託 讓我們把他帶走吧
Please,just let us take him in.
對不起 不行 你們說得沒錯 但是我不能那麼做
Sorry. I can't. I know what you're saying is right,but I can't do it.
對你的損失我深表遺憾 麻煩你放下槍 這樣大家都不會受傷
I'm terribly sorry for your loss,but please just put your guns down so no one else gets hurt.
別逗了 你們寡不敵眾
Are you kidding? You're outnumbered and outgunned.
你覺得現在誰佔上風?
Who do you think has the higher ground here?
肯定是我們啊!
I'm pretty sure we do!
不... 你們... 你們幹嘛?
No... What are you... What are you doing?
咱們還是能抓走他!
We can still take him!
結束了 Joshua
It's over,joshua.
他殺了我媽媽
He killed my mom.
我知道 很遺憾
I know,and I'm sorry.
你衝他開槍?
You shot him?
他死不了
He'll live.
- 滋味不好受 是吧? - 什麼?
- it sucks,doesn't it? - What?
沒有你我們什麼也做不成
Just knowing that we couldn't have done any of this without you.
那可不是
Yeah,pretty much.
我以你為榮 Penelope
I'm proud of you,penelope.
雖然發生那麼多事 你還是回來
Despite everything that happened,you came back...
把工作做完了
And you got the job done.
以前 我會被血淋淋的景象嚇跑
The sight of blood used to make me run away.
兩天前那晚 我卻衝著它跑過去
And two nights ago I ran towards it.
說明你不知不覺變堅強了
It means you're changing into someone stronger than you realize.
你不顧個人安危挽救他人生命
You cared enough to risk your own life to try and save someone else.
是啊 可是...
Yeah,but...
堅強和疲憊不堪有什麼分別?
What's the difference between being strong and being jaded?
我嚇壞了 Derek
I'm scared,derek.
我不想為了能保住飯碗而失去自我
I don't want to lose who I am just so I can do this job.
這地方那麼美
We are in one of the most beautiful places on earth.
- 你也看見了 不是嗎? - 嗯
- I know you see that,don't you? - Yeah.
那就沒什麼好擔心了
Then we have nothing to worry about.
你就是這樣 小妞兒
It's who you are,baby girl.
無論身在何處 你都能發現 萬事萬物的美好之處
You see the beauty in everything and everyone no matter where you go.
這樣的你是不會變的 我也不允許
That part of you is never gonna change,and I won't let it.
- 我不要你保護我 - 這有點困難
- I don't need you to protect me. - Tough.
- 這工作我大概還要做很久 - 是嗎?
- I think I'm gonna stay on the job a little while longer. - Yeah?
要多久?
How much longer?
每天
Every day of my life.
我可真稀罕你啊 Derek Morgan
I kind of love you,derek morgan.
我也稀罕你啊 Penelope Garcia
I kinda love you,penelope garcia.
Ralph W. Sockman曾說 (紐約的基督教牧師)
ralph w. Sockman said,
"沒有什麼 能像溫和的品質一樣有力 也沒有什麼 能像真切的力量一樣溫和"
"nothing is so strong as gentleness,and nothing is so gentle as real strength."
犯罪心理 第五季 第21集 絕命出路
== 結束 ==
Criminal Minds Season05 Episode21 Exit Wounds